SCOTT J. ESPINOSA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Profile

Experienced in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming with a background in delivering reimbursement services & patient support to provide access to therapy. Possess strong skills in team collaboration and proven to quickly take leadership roles within various teams, specializing in working with individuals to promote growth and improve skills

Technical Skills

- JavaScript
- React
- Redux
- Ruby
- Ruby on Rails
- SQLite3
- ActiveRecord
- HTMI
- CSS

Technical Projects

50 STATE VOYAGE | GITHUB - FRONTEND | GITHUB - BACKEND

Travel application to track and plan out future visits to any US state while sharing ideas with friends

- Built the user interface using React with Reactstrap for styling & Redux to manage application state
- Integrated Google API (Maps Javascript & Places APIs) to display business data and locations on a map
- Produced a Rails API backend with a PostgreSQL database and serializers to handle relationships between models
- Utilized JSON Web Tokens for authentication and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side

FIT-TASK-IC | GITHUB - FRONTEND | GITHUB - BACKEND

Goal setting and habit tracking application with graphical representations of accomplishments

- Constructed a user interface using React with Bootstrap 4 styling
- Incorporated multiple graphs with Chart.js to provide visuals of progress towards goals
- · Developed a Rails API backend with serializers to display the user's personal progress and goals
- Utilized JSON Web Tokens for authentication and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side

TRIVIA PARTY | GITHUB

Trivia application to test knowledge and become a high scorer on various quizzes

- Utilized Vanilla Javascript and CSS to implement a single page application
- Scraped an Open Trivia API to provide default quizzes for new users
- Developed a Rails API backend with a PostgreSQL database to manage models and relationships

Work Experience

CAREMETX, LLC

Program Supervisor | 11/2016 - 06/2020 | Oakland, CA

- Collaborated with client's internal programs to help with transitioning new patients onto commercial therapy for client's new product launch
- Conducted performance reviews, provided feedback, and promoted career growth opportunities to 8 direct reports
- Assisted with hiring new employees and created training plans to ramp up employees
- Addressed client escalations by troubleshooting through issues and providing responses

AMERISOURCEBERGEN CONSULTING SERVICES - LASH GROUP

Team Coordinator (Supervisor) | 11/2011 - 10/2016 | San Bruno, CA

- Created standard script team utilized when relaying reimbursement support to providers and patients
- Developed, tested, & launched a new results form and supplemental documents that was sent to providers
- Completed complex weekly analysis of program data for client and senior/executive leadership review
- Increased productivity & quality by 20% in a year through motivation feedback sessions & interactive trainings

Contact Information

650-580-5544 | South San Francisco, CA 94080

Email: scottjames.espinosa@gmail.com
Portfolio: https://scottespinosa.com
Github: https://github.com/sfespinosa
Blog: https://medium.com/@scottespinosa

Education

FLATIRON SCHOOL

San Francisco, CA | 06/2020 - 09/2020

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA, DAVIS Davis, CA | 09/2005 - 06/2009

BS, Biochemistry & Molecular Biology